

I believe software is increasingly complex, but they need not be complicated.

I am a Human-Computer Interaction researcher currently working in the domain of media discovery & recommendation. My vision in general is to improve technology in general to make it more usable and especially accessibility. I generally approach this by first identifying a problem, hypothesizing solutions, and later testing with prototypes and user-studies. I find that this approach leverages my prior experiences as sysadmin and technical team lead reasonably well, and leads to good research findings.

#### EDUCATION

Masters of Computer Science · Baylor University · 2012–2014

THESIS: Giving the Users a Hand: Towards Touchless Hand Gestures for the Desktop

Bachelor of Computer Science · Coventry University · 2002–2005 THESIS: Remote PC Manipulation via PDA over Bluetooth

### PUBLICATIONS

USA), ACM (2014)

Improving Gestural Interaction With Augmented Cursors Ashley Dover, G. Michael Poor, Darren Guinness, and Alvin Jude SUI '16 ACM Symposium on Spatial User Interaction (Tokyo, Japan), ACM (to appear) (2016)

Grasp, Grab or Pinch? Identifying User Preference for In-Air Gestural Manipulation Alvin Jude, G. Michael Poor, and Darren Guinness SUI '16 ACM Symposium on Spatial User Interaction (Tokyo, Japan), ACM (to appear) (2016)

Reporting and Visualizing Fitts Law: Dataset, Tools and Methodologies Alvin Jude, Darren Guinness, and G. Michael Poor CHI '16 Extended Abstracts on Human Factors in Computing Systems, (San Jose, CA), ACM (2016)

Evaluating Item-Item Similarity Algorithms for Movies Lucas Colucci, Prachi Doshi, Kun-Lin Lee, Jiajie Liang, Yin Lin, Ishan Vashishtha, Jia Zhang, and Alvin Jude CHI '16 Extended Abstracts on Human Factors in Computing Systems, (San Jose, CA), ACM (2016)

Models for Rested Touchless Gestural Interaction Darren Guinness, Alvin Jude, G. Michael Poor, and Ashley Dover SUI '15 ACM Symposium on Spatial User Interaction (Los Angeles, CA, USA), ACM (2015)

Modeling Mid-air Gestures With Spherical Coordinates Darren Guinness, Andrew Seung, Ashley Dover, G. Michael Poor, and Alvin Jude SUI '15 ACM Symposium on Spatial User Interaction (Los Angeles, CA, USA), ACM (2015)

Personal Space: User Defined Gesture Space for GUI Interaction. Alvin Jude, G. Michael Poor, and Darren Guinness CHI '14 Extended Abstracts on Human Factors in Computing Systems, (Toronto, Canada), ACM (2014)

An Evaluation of Touchless Hand Gestural Interaction for Pointing Tasks with Preferred and Non-preferred Hands. Alvin Jude, G. Michael Poor, and Darren Guinness NordiCHI '14 Proceedings of the 8th Nordic Conference on Human-Computer Interaction, (Helsinki, Finland), ACM (2014)

Evaluating Multimodal Interaction with Gestures and Speech for Point and Select Tasks Alvin Jude, G. Michael Poor, and Darren Guinness

NordiCHI '14 Proceedings of the 8th Nordic Conference on Human-Computer Interaction (Helsinki, Finland), ACM (2014)

Gestures with Speech for Hand-Impaired Persons Darren Guinness, G. Michael Poor, and Alvin Jude ASSETS '14 Proceedings of the 16th International ACM SIGACCESS Conference on Computers and Accessibility (New York, NY,

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

 $Basic : Photoshop \cdot CSS_3 \cdot HTML_5 \cdot Ember.js \cdot Cassandra \cdot Nagios \cdot Qualitative \ Research \cdot Machine \ Learning \\ Intermediate : Python \cdot PHP_5 \cdot LATEX \cdot JQuery \cdot MySQL \cdot R \cdot Matlab \cdot Java \cdot Recommender \ Systems \cdot Personalisation \\ Advanced : User \ Experience (UX) \cdot Usability \ Testing \cdot Experimental \ Design \cdot Hypothesis \ Testing \cdot Gestural \ Interaction \\ Interaction \ Testing \cdot Systems \cdot Personalisation \ Testing \cdot Systems \cdot Systems \cdot Personalisation \ Testing \cdot Systems \cdot Systems \cdot Personalisation \ Testing \cdot Systems \cdot Systems$ 

### OTHER SKILLS

COMMUNICATION : Former Malaysian Public Speaking Champion

Entrepreneurship : Baylor NewVenture 2014: Top-5 Finalist & 3rd place Elevator Pitch Martial Arts : Taekwondo (3<sup>rd</sup> Dan Black Belt), Karate, Aikido, MMA, Krav Maga

### WORK EXPERIENCE

# Ericsson · 2014–present · Researcher

Improved discovery of similar items by 38%. Led usability testing of new content discovery methods with a European partner. Currently also performs self-driven research for patent portfolio, a next-generation media delivery platform, and research collaboration with academic partners.

Reference: Nimish Radia · nimish.radia@ericsson.com

# Baylor University · 2013–2014 · Research Assistant

Setup new HCI lab. Mentored juniors, established engineering procedures and infrastructure. Performed research in hand-gestural interaction and explored research options with other next-generation input devices. Overhauled software used for teaching database. Assisted in developing lab curriculum for teaching operating systems.

Reference: G. Michael Poor · michael poor@baylor.edu Reference: Greg Speegle · greg\_speegle@baylor.edu

# Self Employed · 2010–2012 · Technical Consultant

Served as an independent consultant for various project and companies including the following:

# iOS Development, Agile Perspectives — Malaysia, 2011–2012

Performed R&D for use of Apple products in financial services. Built and deployed app for one international insurance corporation. Built app for a consumer-facing startup dealing in retail. Role included requirements gathering, feasibility studies, business case development, and technical consultation.

### System Administration, CouchSurfing.org, 2010–2011

Deployed a cluster of static content servers with NGinX to reduce the load off the dynamic servers, which resulted in higher reliability or website as a whole. Tools of the trade included Puppet, Zabbix, HAProxy.

# Aflexi · 2009–2010 · System Engineer

Aflexi was a CDN Software startup, and is currently a division of OnApp. Responsibilities were more DevOps involving backend development and system administration. Built a monitoring infrastructure from the ground up (traditionally done with Nagios) with custom scripts running on a specialized Collectd infrastructure; used to feed PowerDNS for DNS-based CDN routing. Tools of the trade included Puppet, Zabbix, Nagios, Reprepro, RRD.

Reference: Whei Wong · whei.wong@onapp.com

### iMocha Consulting · 2007–2010 · Team Lead

Initially hired as a Junior Java Developer, but quickly tasked to build and run a LAMP team of up to 8 people, dealing mostly with financial institutions. Responsibilities included hiring, firing, and mentoring programmers, system administrators, system analysts, and interns, as well as requirements gathering from clients.

Reference: Koh Kok Wei kokwei@imocha.com.my

# Sony Manufacturing · 2005–2007 · Engineer

Developed Linux-based software required for manufacturing. Developed a tool used to trace products which helped cut down tracability time from 2 working days to about 4 hours. Tools of the trade included MFC, VB.NET, PHP, Postgres, GTK.